# Sugeesh Liyanage

Life-long seeker of knowledge and Business IT & Coding Booot Camp graduate who currently has his sights set on a full-time web development position. Experienced in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Meteor, Firebase, Ionic Mobile Framework, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB & React.JS. Additionally, knowledgeable in the graphic designing as well as Accounting Packages.

#### **SKILLS**

Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, UI, JavaScript, JQuery, responsive design, React, Bootstrap, API, AJAX, Meteor Knowledgeable in NODE, Express, MongoDB, Sequelize, MySQL, ChartJS, Firebase and PHP

#### **EDUCATION**

The University of Texas, Austin, TX UT Coding Bootcamp - Javascript Full Stack Web Development	January 2018 - July 2018
Central Piedmont Community College, Charlotte, NC Frontend Developer Certification	January 2015 – June 2015
University of Greenwich, London, UK BSc Hons in Business IT – First Class equivalent to GPA: 3.8	January 2008 - June 2011

### APPLICATIONS BUILT

## **Soccer Team Management App**

This app will provide Players and Teams Statistics, according to the statistics players can improve their weak statistics and play better in the next game of soccer.

- Add Player, Team Statistics & User login & Password
- https://soccer-superapp.herokuapp.com/

# Bamazon, Lead Developer

- A command line node app that emulates an online store.
- Developed app using Node implemented inquirer, Mysql, Table, Colors Node packages.
- <a href="https://github.com/SugeeshLiyanage/bamazon">https://github.com/SugeeshLiyanage/bamazon</a>

#### CommunicatED

This app facilitate communication between parents and administrators concerning student behavior. Using this app teachers can keep track of a student's behavior good or bad.

- Firebase Authentication, Adding student behaviors.
- https://peaceful-dawn-41880.herokuapp.com/

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Sugeesh Liyanage, Web Developer, Austin, Tx – Web Developer

January 2018 – Present

- Created clean, responsive websites for clients, utilizing HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and JQuery
- Optimized sites for mobile responsiveness

Pacotech Inc. May 2016 – Present

Customer Service, Metadata Clerk, Delivery

• Provide public information request verification and fulfillment for the Texas Commission on Environmental Quality.

## ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

## UmaOya Project, Sri Lanka

April 2010 - Nov 2014

Management Assistant

- Updated Sri Lanka Foreign Aid Budget Monitoring System website, (http://www.pmm.gov.lk/).
- Used Access to create, populate, and backup databases and to create queries and reports.
- Prepared Bank Reconciliation statements every month.
- Create new file labels Using GBS Netlabels according to public requests & customer requirement.